CHOIR:
♪ The Simpsons ♪
(tires screeching)
D’oh!
(screams)
(tires screeching)
(clicking)
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
-(alarm rings)
-(Homer groans)
(yawns)
Hmm.
I must be supposed
to remember something.
Huh?
Huh. Hmm.
Come on. memory. wake up.
(grunting)
Is it our anniversary?
No. we don’t have
one this year.
Hmm.
Hm-hmm...
(coughs)
Don’t forge?
Don’t forge what?
(coughs)
-Oh... don’t forget.
-(giggles)
Don’t forget what?
Hustle your
bustles. gang.
We’re going to the Senior
Olympics to root for Grampa.
The Senior Olympics?
That’s what I was supposed
to remember?!
(groaning):
Oh...
Don’t you dare go limp.
Too late. The deed is done.
Kids. grab a fold.
(Bart. Lisa.
and Marge grunting)
(door shuts. telephone rings)
MOE (on answering machine):
Oh. hey. Homer.
Uh. I hope you didn’t forget
that today’s our big day.
I sure am looking forward
to my birthday fishing trip.
(chuckles)
Well. I’ll see you soon.
This is Moe. big day.
Uh... waiting.
feeling. uh. kind of fragile.
Moe. the birthday boy.
listening for your car.
(sobbing)
(tired moaning)
I can finally win
a gold medal.
I came close
at the 1936 Olympics.
♪♪
I threw a javelin
that barely missed Hitler.
But I did hit an assassin
who was trying to kill Hitler.
What is this?
Kill Hitler Day?
The next time I saw Hitler.
we had dinner
and laughed about it.
♪♪
What’s with the lined
composition book?
My report on a "Fascinating
Springfielder" is due Monday.
and everybody I’ve tried
to interview is so boring.
(Marge groans)
You could interview me.
I collect
Absolut ads.
How many others
do you have?
(gasps)
There are others?
HOMER:
This guy sucks.
He can barely make it
to the top.
("Rocky the Flying Squirrel"
theme music playing)
(applause)
(groans)
72 lousy events
and Grampa hasn’t won
a single medal.
Well. it’s not fair
when Moleman uses
his replacement legs.
(chuckles)
On your mark!
(grunting)
Oh...
Oh. it’s clouding up.
I better
put on me rain poncho.
(wheezing)
Sir!
You dropped your munchers!
(yells. frightened)
(yelling in Scottish)
You’ll never take me alive.
Grim Reaper!
(grunting)
(applause)
Yay. Grampa.
Take the boy.
His soul is fresher.
(sniffs)
I’ve never been happier.
("Star-Spangled Banner"
plays)
Turn that hippie crap off!
I wonder if the dog thought
about us while we were gone.
(sad music plays)
(gasps) Oh... I was supposed
to take Moe fishing today.
Everybody hide!
Finally.
that jerk Homer is home.
(tires screeching)
Oh. it’s just his car.
MOE:
♪ Happy birthday to me ♪
♪ I feel so damn lonely ♪
♪ Won’t someone kill me... ♪
(sobbing)
♪ And many more. ♪
Homer. we can’t scuttle
like crabs
for the rest
of our lives.
Says you.
♪♪
(dinging)
(moaning)
"Dear Pus Bag"?
Whoa. Marge. who’d
you piss off?
It’s for you. Pus Bag!
(groans sadly)
MOE: Birthdays never meant
squat to me.
Then you offered
to take me fishing.
and like a stumblebum chump.
I dared to hope.
But you shattered my dreams
like a Duff tall boy
in a bar brawl.
and you jammed the jagged neck
right up my heart’s butt.
I guess I just wasn’t meant
to be happy or handsome
or anything. really.
(sighs)
What a deep. tormented soul.
(gasps)
DRIVER:
Loser!
(sighs)
(sighs louder)
(thunder)
(sighs)
LISA: Moe!
You have a worldview
both bleak and beautiful.
I want to write a report
about you.
Wow. for the first time
in my life.
someone’s taking
a genuine interest
in what’s inside of me.
Heh. suddenly. this is
my best birthday ever.
Still in the top three.
Still in the top ten.
How come you wanna
do a report on me?
I ain’t no great man. like
Bob Seger or Haystacks Calhoun.
Because I suspect deep
within you is an artist’s soul.
Thanks.
So here’s my digs.
Moe. you live in a hotel?
You’re just like "Eloise"!
Did someone say my name?
This vibrating massage
chair feels great!
That ain’t a massage chair.
It’s just full of cockroaches.
See?
LISA: Hmm...
Wow!
Moe. these fragments
are fascinating.
"I was in the Christmas
pageant once.
Mom showed up
with a new boyfriend.
He called me Steve."
Oh... what you’ve got here
is poetry!
(high-pitched voice):
Ooh. Moe’s a poet!
He has a soul!
Flutter your wings!
It’s teatime in
Buttercup Junction!
♪ Dee-dee-dee... ♪
(yells)
(groaning)
Moe’s the Princess
of Lollipop Land!
-(groaning)
-(cat meows)
He lunches
on lavender and potpourri!
(yells)
(clattering)
Seriously. Moe.
I think you have a gift.
Thanks. Homer.
I love ya. man.
Ooh. you love a man!
You know. artfully arranged.
these fragments could be
an epic poem-- like T.S.
Eliot’s "The Wasteland."
What-which why-liot’s
the who-now?
Whoa!
My brain-goo’s comin’ out all
artistical. thanks to you.
How ’bout this
for a title:
"Howling at a Concrete Moon."
That’s a terrific title!
It jumps out at you like a rat
in your underwear drawer.
We make a great
team there. Liser.
(sheepish chuckling)
"...my soul smells like a dead
pigeon after three weeks.
I shut my window
and go to sleep.
In my dream I eat corn
with my eyes."
Philistines.
Lisa. I’m sorry you
got a bad grade on
your "Moe and tell."
I don’t care about my grade.
I’m gonna send Moe’s poem to
American Poetry Perspectives.
Do not mention that
publication in this house!
They never published
my poem!
"There once was
a rapping tomato
That’s right.
I said ’rapping tomato’
He rapped all day
from April to May
And also. guess what.
it was me."
(grunts)
Hey. Chief. we just
got a submission
from a brilliant poet
no one’s ever heard of!
(grunting)
Hmm!
Genius!
Pay him nothing.
and run it on the cover!
Stop the presses!
Send my wife some flowers!
And bring me an Advil!
What do you mean
you don’t work for me?!
You’re hired!
Now that you’re hired.
you’re fired!
Now that you don’t work here.
we can be friends.
Now that we’re friends.
how come you never call?
Some friend you are!
God. I love this business.
Here it is.
Bad news. Maya Angelou:
you’ve been bumped.
(indistinct yelling)
...you can’t bump me...
...bump you!
(indistinct yelling)
Moe.
you’re a published author!
Wow. Just think:
earlier tonight.
a newly-published poet
cleaned up my barf.
(phone rings)
Moe’s Tavern.
Who?
Where?
To what?
Screw you. snail trail!
Who was that?
Eh. some jerk makin’
a prank call
with a gag name:
"Tom Wolfe."
Tom Wolfe?!
He wrote The Right Stuff
and Bonfire of the Vanities.
And coined the phrase
"radical chic!" (groans)
Wait. wait. wait. Then that
guy wasn’t squeezin’ my ’roids
when he invited me to the
Wordloaf Festival in Vermont?
(gasps)
The Wordloaf Festival?!
You’ll meet all the great
American writers. Moe!
You have to go!
Yeah? Well. okay. all right.
but uh... only if you come. huh?
Ah. I wouldn’t-a had none
of this without you. kid.
(phone rings)
Hello.
Oh. hey. Milhouse.
I’m not here.
Ah. a family trip with
the family bartender--
what could be better?
How’s it goin’. Homer?
Oh. lousy.
I gotta go to Vermont
for some stupid poetry thing.
Homer. don’t
drink and drive!
Fine.
I’ll drive between sips.
(tires screech)
(slurps)
(tires screech. slurps)
Whoop!
They got an open bar
at this thing. right?
Wow. Troopers from every state
in New England.
Including Rhode Island!
We’re a small state.
but we give big tickets.
Hey. guys. didja hear?
The Da Vinci Code just sold
one hundred million copies!
(groaning)
(chuckles)
(elegant music plays)
(gasps):
It’s Tom Wolfe!
He uses more
exclamation points
than any other major
American writer.
It’s true!
How ya doin’ there?
Uh. Moe Szyslak.
Ah. magnificent Moe.
He stands. stoop-shouldered.
blinking in the light.
hollow-chested like
a dough-faced fall guy
who’s made a career of taking
dives but has decided
to get his manhood out of hock
and take a shot at the title--
or at least go for
the jaw and-- thwack--
hyperextend the
champ’s pterygoideus
before kissing
the mat good night.
MOE:
You ever scrub your hands
real fast. and you think
you’re seein’ a third one?
One time I looked down
and there really was.
I gotta get a new lock
for that bathroom.
(all laughing)
Moe. your debut poem
is as refreshing
as a second pair of
socks on a wet hike.
I must know how you came up
with that brilliant title.
"Howling at a Concrete Moon."
Uh. well actually. I had
some help on the title...
(all gasping)
You needed help
to write your title?
Well. so have I.
Gore Vidal.
1876 was the price
I paid for gas once.
I thought of Burr
when I saw it written
on an Eskimo Pie package.
I can’t believe it!
Those sound like
terrible jokes!
Sir. I must ask you to
pick up your gift bag
and leave this festival.
I don’t need
your sycophantic laughter!
I have some on tape.
(sycophantic laughter)
You still love me.
Temple University Class
of 1987.
So Moe. you were telling us
how you came up with your title.
Yeah. well. I-I was just saying
that um...
...that I. uh. I thought it up
all by myself.
(gasps)
Ah. like a real writer.
Outstanding. Moe!
To the hayride!
(all cheering)
♪ Let’s get it started ♪
♪ Let’s get it started in here.
let’s get it started... ♪
(resounding clang)
But we were a team!
(cheering and laughter)
(sobbing)
-♪ Let’s get it started... ♪
-(laughing continues)
I’d like
to introduce our panel:
Jonathan Franzen.
Michael Chabon. and Moe.
Whoa. clear water.
Swanky! Whoo-hoo.
Now we’ll open the floor
to fawning praise
and obvious questions.
(Lisa grunting)
Uh. yeah. first of all.
I’d like to thank all of you
for your brilliant work.
(applause)
Yes. yes.
My question is. who are
your biggest influences?
I’d have to say
my good friend Jonathan Franzen.
I thought his novel
The Corrections needed none.
Cha-bone...!
Well. in turn. I’d have to say
my biggest influence is...
Albert Camus.
You were supposed
to say me.
I blurbed you.
Yeah. and it looks
real sweet on my dust jacket.
How do you like me now?
Fran-zone...!
Moe. who inspired you
to become a writer?
Jack Kerouac?
Charles Bukowski?
Me. Tom Wolfe?
Well. I dunno. uh...
the only book I ever read
was Super Hounds: The Ultimate
Greyhound Betting System.
So. uh. any of you. uh.
Wet-Naps write that?
(laughter)
Mr. Szyslak. there
must be some person.
possibly in this very room.
who believed in you
when no one else did.
Oh. uh. yeah.
I get what you’re gettin’ at.
Um... nope.
But how can you...?
Now. now. he’s answered
your question.
I declare this panel
dismissed.
-(bangs gavel)
-But I deserve acknowledgement.
-I said dismissed.
Lisa. grab your
sightseeing shoes.
We’re going Vermonting.
It’s gonna be awesome.
Man. couples in this state
sure like to clink glasses.
(sighs sadly)
You guys go ahead.
I don’t think
I’d be very good company.
Hey. thanks
for the heads up.
We’ll see you
when we see you.
(sighs)
I love these
covered bridges.
It’s like driving through
cute little houses.
That was my house.
you moron.
Oh. I’m sorry.
We should exchange
insurance information.
I have none.
(geese honking)
(grunting)
No food for you
grad students
till you grade
3.000 papers.
(yelling)
Hey. hey.
there you are.
I’ve been
lookin’ for ya.
I need a brilliant new poem
for the farewell dinner.
So if you could turn
these into one of those
and then don’t say nothin’
while I take all the credit.
I’d really appreciate it.
though I’d never admit that.
And. look. I got you started.
Huh? Huh?
Moe. you’re a heartless jerk.
Huh? Whoa.
where did that come from?
Oh. right. right. my actions.
Well. let’s see if I can put
this poem together.
Hmm. Hmm. Hmm. Hmm.
Hah!
Hey. hey. hey.
Hey. st-stupid geese.
you’re eatin’ my brilliance.
-(geese squawking)
-Hey. hey.
I will break your beak.
What... Get... Hey...
Look at me.
It’s supposed to be
my big triumph.
and I’m standing in mud.
fightin’ with geese.
Well. if I’m gonna fight.
I might as well win.
(gunshots. geese honking)
Yeah. go on. you cowards.
Fly off in a "V."
Hey. Lis. we learned so much
scootin’ around Vermont.
Did you know that candles
are made by losers?
And we went to the Vermont
Teddy Bear Factory.
Look what we got.
Hmm? Hmm?
(crying)
Oh. honey. don’t cry.
They’re not made
from real bears--
just their fur and noses.
Moe marginalized
my contributions.
(both gasp)
(crying)
No one makes my
daughter sob and run.
He ruined
her first Wordloaf.
Look at me. sittin’ here
depressed when I’m surrounded
by the happiest people
in the world: writers.
-(clinking)
-Before Moe reads
his keynote poem.
I would like to stake my claim
to any unfinished
garlic mashed potatoes.
So please. if you would pass
them clockwise up to table one.
I will collect them later.
Now. I give you Moe Szyslak.
(applause)
Uh. this here poem is called
"Elevator Capacity."
(Moe clears throat)
"Elevator capacity:
2.400 pounds.
Inspection Certificate
available
in hotel manager’s office."
You just pulled that
off the wall of the elevator.
Yeah. well. uh. uh. here’s
another one you might like.
(clears throat)
"Channel 61: Family Favorites.
Channel 62: Adult Desires.
Channel 63: In-Room Checkout.
Chan..."
You know what?
I got a different poem for yaz.
(shocked murmuring)
Ode to Lisa:
Pointy-headed mini-muse
More friend than I deserved
You pulled me from the dirt
And made me
the beautiful flower
that I am.
But some flowers
can stab you in the back
For which I should
send you flowers
Which I will.
but they were closed
You’ll be
getting them tomorrow.
Oh. Moe.
Lisa. if you could
just forgive me.
you would make me
the happiest man in Vermont.
Except for those two dudes
I saw gettin’ hitched.
Not my thing. but
I wish ’em well.
Make my daughter
cry. will ya.
Eat syrup. jerk.
Wha...?
Dad. no!
I’m not mad at Moe anymore.
Uh. Homer.
would it make you feel better
if. uh. any of that hit me?
HOMER:
No. not now.
I’m gonna
walk away then. Okay?
Wow. You couldn’t
make this stuff up.
Well. you couldn’t.
That’s it. Franzen.
I think your nose
needs some corrections.
(both grunting)
Ooh. you fight
like Anne Rice.
Well. Moe. I guess
we’re friends again.
That’s great.
Now what do you say we do some
regional duck pin bowling?
I’d like that.
I’d like it a lot.
Aw. that’s sweet.
I hate sweet.
I need photos.
Photos of Spider-Man.
This is a
poetry journal.
Okay. then poems
about Spider-Man.
And I want them finished
before you start.
And before you finish.
get me some coffee.
And the poems should have
the following rhyme scheme:
A-B-B-A-A-B-B-A-C-D-E-C-D-E.
What are you waitin’ for.
Chinese New Year?
♪♪
Captioned by VISUAL DATA
Hmm.
Maple syrup.
Sleigh on the label--
very good.
Rich maple color.
good swirl.
(sniffing)
(slurping. gulping)
(nonsense sounds)
(gargling)
Oh... Jemima!
(groaning)
Touched
in the head. is he?
A-yup.
Shh!
Enhanced by Fotokem
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org